<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<executable>
  <category>HistomicsTK</category>
  <title>PodoCount</title>
  <description>PodoCount</description>
  <version>0.1.0</version>
  <documentation-url>https://github.com/SarderLab/PodoCount</documentation-url>
  <license>Apache 2.0</license>
  <contributor>Sumanth Devarasetty (University of Florida)</contributor>
  <acknowledgements>This work is part of efforts in digital pathology by the Sarder Lab: UFL.</acknowledgements>
  <parameters>
    <label>IO</label>
    <description>Input/Output Parameters</description>
    <string-enumeration>
      <name>type</name>
      <label>Analysis Type</label>
      <description>Type of Analysis: "Human Analysis" or "Mouse Analysis"</description>
      <default>Human</default>
      <element>Human</element>
      <element>Mouse</element>
      <index>0</index>
    </string-enumeration>
    <image>
      <name>input_image</name>
      <label>Input Image</label>
      <description>Input Filename</description>
      <channel>input</channel>
      <index>1</index>
    </image>
    <directory>
      <name>basedir</name>
      <label>Base Directory</label>
      <description>Parent folder or collection for the current image</description>
      <channel>input</channel>
      <index>2</index>
    </directory>
    <double>
      <name>slider</name>
      <label>Slider</label>
      <description> Slider control fine-tunes a threshold used to identify nuclei. Typically a setting of 1 for Slider is effective for murine images and 2.5 for Human images. Adjusting the Slider value above 1 results in fewer podocytes being detected. Decreasing the Slider below 1 results in detecting a larger number of podocytes, while also including noise. Cases where the Slider value of 1 detects structural noise, increase the Slider in steps of 0.5 to improve podocyte segmentation. Adjust Slider accordingly in [0,3]</description>
      <channel>input</channel>
      <index>3</index>
    </double>
    <integer>
      <name>section_thickness</name>
      <label>Section Thickness</label>
      <description> Tissue section thickness in μm [0,15]</description>
      <channel>input</channel>
      <index>4</index>
    </integer>
    <string-enumeration>
      <name>num_sections</name>
      <label>Number of Sections</label>
      <description>The number of tissue sections per slide; for WSIs of murine whole kidney sections options are 1 or 2, for human biopsy data, set to 1</description>
      <default>1</default>
      <element>1</element>
      <element>2</element>
      <index>5</index>
    </string-enumeration>
    <double>
      <name>ihc_gauss_sd</name>
      <label>IHC Guassian SD</label>
      <description> This parameter tunes the smoothness of the immunohistochemistry (IHC) image intensity that is being processed. A higher value results in greater smoothing, and thus is useful for reducing noise and highlighting significant patterns. Conversely, a lower value preserves fine structures. The default value set for this parameter is 2, try increasing/decreasing accordingly in steps of 0.5 to check for a better segmentation</description>
      <default>2.0</default>
      <channel>input</channel>
      <index>6</index>
    </double>
    <double>
      <name>dt_gauss_sd</name>
      <label>DT Guassian SD</label>
      <description> This parameter stabilizes target structures via filtering morphological noise. A lower value leads to less stability enhancing a larger number of podocyte dectection. If the default value misses detecting some podocytes, gradually decrease the value in increments of 0.25. Such stepwise reduction reveals more podocytes but be cautious as this approach enhances detecting small structural noise as podocytes. Increasing the value of this parameter reduces the detection of erroneous smaller structures. This process is particularly useful for images where the staining related intensity as well as structural noise is high. If the segmentation results include too many irrelevant structures, consider incrementally increasing this parameter to acheive a clear segmentation with a focus on the most significant podocytes</description>
      <default>1.0</default>
      <channel>input</channel>
      <index>7</index>
    </double>
    <double>
      <name>emt_thresh</name>
      <label>EMT Threshold</label>
      <description> This parameter controls the cutoff to eliminate structural noise. The default value of the parameter is 0.01</description>
      <default>0.01</default>
      <channel>input</channel>
      <index>8</index>
    </double>
    <description>The following parameters are only used in the podocyte segmentation for human images</description>
    <integer>
      <name>max_major</name>
      <label>Max Major Axis Length</label>
      <description> Sets the upper limit for the major axis length of detected podocyte structures assuming the associated shapes resembles ellipse. Useful for excluding abnormally large structures from the segmentation. Choose a value in [30,100]. The default is 60</description>
      <default>60</default>
      <channel>input</channel>
      <index>9</index>
    </integer>
    <integer>
      <name>min_minor</name>
      <label>Min Minor Axis Length</label>
      <description> Defines the lower limit for the minor axis of detected podocyte structures. Useful for filtering out smaller, potentially irrelevant objects. Choose a value in [5,30]. Default value is 10</description>
      <default>10</default>
      <channel>input</channel>
      <index>10</index>
    </integer>
    <double>
      <name>max_ecc</name>
      <label>Max Eccentricity</label>
      <description> Specifies the maximum allowed eccentricity of the detected podocyte structures. A lower value limits the analysis to more circular objects, while a higher value includes more elongated shapes. Select a value in the range [0.5,0.9]. Default is 0.7</description>
      <default>0.7</default>
      <channel>input</channel>
      <index>11</index>
    </double>
  </parameters>
  <parameters advanced="true">
    <label>Girder API URL and Key</label>
    <description>A Girder API URL and token for Girder client</description>
    <string>
      <name>girderApiUrl</name>
      <longflag>api-url</longflag>
      <label>Girder API URL</label>
      <description>A Girder API URL (e.g., https://girder.example.com:443/api/v1)</description>
      <default></default>
    </string>
    <string>
      <name>girderToken</name>
      <longflag>token</longflag>
      <label>Girder API Token</label>
      <description>A Girder token identifying a user session</description>
      <default></default>
    </string>
  </parameters>
</executable>